Daniel Styles

Goose Creek, SC | dstyles0612@gmail.com | (843) 793-9064

Objective

IT professional with a strong interest in information security, information assurance, and systems administration. Hard-working, energetic, personable, and technical-minded individual. Possesses exceptional customer service and communication skills with a strong ability to multitask and resolve issues quickly. Currently in an IT role where I continue to develop and learn new skills while contributing to the overall success of the organization. I also possess experience in:

- Operating Systems: Windows 10, Windows Server 2016, Linux (Debian, CentOS, and Kali), and macOS.
- VMs: VMware, VirtualBox, and Microsoft's Hyper-V.
- Scripting languages: Python and Bash hobbyist

Education

Charleston Southern University -- Bachelors of Technology in Cyber Security

August 2021 - ~2023

Trident Technical College -- Associates Degree in Applied Sciences in Cyber Security

Acquired May 2021

Trident Technical College -- Associates Degree in Applied Sciences in Network Systems Management

Acquired May 2021

Trident Technical College -- Certificate in Network Security

Acquired May 2021

Trident Technical College -- Certificate in CompTIA Systems Specialist

Acquired May 2021

Trident Technical College -- Continuing Education

Acquired Summer 2019

- Security+ course (4 CEUs)
- Certified Ethical Hacker course (4 CEUs)

Certifications

CompTIA Security+ CE

Acquired March 2020

Work Experience

Charleston County School District, Charleston, SC -- IT Field Technician II (Contract to Hire)

July 2020 - Present 40 Hours/Week \$44,256

- Obtained the 2nd highest Service Level Agreement score of 98% YTD out of all field technicians in the first 6 months of work.
- Successfully solve networking and hardware issues with Windows and Apple products, including desktops, laptops, mobile devices, and SmartBoards.
- Replace defective hardware elements in desktops, laptops, and Chromebooks.
- Perform routine software updates to desktops, laptops, Chromebooks, and Promethean boards.
- Collaborate with teachers and staff on solving information technology issues within a strict time window.
- Proficient use of the HEAT ticketing system to manage daily tasks.

Gildan USA, Charleston, SC -- Equipment Operator

May 2014 - July 2020 40 Hours/Week \$29,088

- Communicated with ground team members and operators to prevent safety hazards.
- Met daily load and unload goals set from each previous year.
- Operate various forklifts safely and efficiently on a team of over 80 employees.
- Support inbound/outbound activities through careful precision and effectiveness.

Journey's Shoes, Charleston, SC -- Sales promoted to Co-Manager

September 2012 - May 2014 40-50 Hours/Week \$24,960

- Oversaw employee performance, corrected problems, and increased efficiency to maintain productivity targets.
- Trained new employees on proper protocols and customer service standards.
- Multiplied earnings through sales goal achievements, customer service improvements, and commitment to team objectives.
- Submitted weekly reports to senior management to aid in business decision-making and planning.

Skills

- Configured networks using Cisco routers and switches by utilizing proper cabling techniques, troubleshooting issues using the OSI model, implementing proper subnetting to satisfy network requirements, and using best security practices when configuring devices in a lab setting.
- Experience with Linux system administration by using command-line tools to manage local users and groups, monitoring and managing foreground and background processes, and implementing proper control over services and daemons in a class setting. Experience with Debian, CentOS, and Kali Linux.
- Created automation scripts in Bash and Python to assist in the precision and efficiency of administrative tasks in a class setting.
- DoD 8570.01-m Compliant
- Information Assurance Technical (IAT) Level II
- Information Assurance Management (IAM) Level I

Extracurricular Activities

- Trident Technical College Cyber Security Club Attend meetings to further my education on topics not taught in class. Prepare for competitions, such as the National Cyber League and the South Eastern Conference Cyber Defense Competition.
- Test my offensive security abilities on platforms such as Hack The Box, Try Hack Me, and Over the Wire Wargames.
- Use other information technology learning platforms such as PentesterLab, Pentester Academy, ITPro TV, INE Training, TCM Academy, and Azeria Labs to broaden and enhance my knowledge on information systems.